<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid/>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Miscellaneous Scrap Book<num>PBY100.A</num> <num>PBY100.A</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Stage</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-09 09:26:04 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Stage</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Miscellaneous Scrap Book</unittitle>
      <unitid>PBY100.A</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1950" type="inclusive">1935-1950</unitdate>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_d0ffae7b44a665f34adb5e07d2aa8737">English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_9dc4d4f8c13dadd35d5edb84f203683d">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>This scrap book was assembled by Eva Gilbert who was the first "curator" of the Peabody Room from 1935 to 1950. It is surmised that the ephemera contained in this scrap book was donated by library patrons to the Peabody Room after its opening in October of 1935.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b0a2aebd627e43c010dbec605eaa08a9">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>The scrap book measures 10.5" x 12" and contains 75 pages that are numbered in pencil in the lower edge corner to assist in locating described ephemera. These materials have been indexed by ephemera type and then alphabetically under each category. The oldest document is from 1786 and the newest is from 1944.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <processinfo id="aspace_8100f543761132e4b96e6a1559bccf24">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Eva Gilbert glued each document into the scrap book, probably in the order that the items were donated. Most documents were affixed to only one side of each page. Acid free sheets have been placed between each page.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <index id="aspace_bb8c5c0828164b761a39fcd842c63add">
      <head>Subject Index</head>
      <p>ADMITTANCE TICKETS Female Seminary, July 29, 1842. Issued to Mr. and Mrs. Craigin to the Exercises in Music. Page 5. Linthicum Hall. Musical concert benefit for Market Street Chapel, May 12, 1893. Page 16. BILLS OF LADING Guy, Alexander, April 22, 1825. Shipment of 18 bales of wool from Guy to Bullock &amp; Davis in Philadelphia aboard the sloop Constitution docked in Alexandria. Page 50. BROADSIDES "Grand Vocal and Instrumental Concert of Prof. Derwort, His Three Daughters, and Son," Pompeian Hall, January 1, 1850. Pompeian Hall was located in the Union Hotel on the northeast corner of M and 30th Streets, NW. Page 13. BUSINESS CARDS Jackson, R. Plummer, "Agency for Claims," Bridge Street (M Street, NW). Page 7. Union Hotel, E. R. Abbott, Proprietor, Bridge and Washington Street (M and 30th Street, NW). Page 7. CERTIFICATES (SCHOOL) Female Seminary, Georgetown, DC. Two certificates issued to Mary Virginia Adler, June 26, 1843 and February 11, 1847. Signed by Lydia English. Page 15. Georgetown College. Issued in 1834 to "Ingenuo adolescenti" Washington Ward. Certificate in Latin features college seal with affixed red wax seal and blue ribbon. Page 3. Georgetown College. Issued in 1864 to "Ingenuo adolescenti" Joanni Lutz.. Certificate in Latin features college seal. Page 36. CERTIFICATES (STOCK) Washington Totine Company. Two shares of capital stock worth $50 each issued July 11, 1805 to Mary Ann Caton ("Grand daughter of Charles Carroll of Carrolltown") by Benjamin Stoddert, "Agent &amp; Director." Page 38. CURRENCY The Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Canal Company, $5.00 note #1769 issued in Washington, DC on August 9, 1840. Page 6. The Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Canal Company, $5.00 note #1090 issued in Washington, DC on July 9, 1840. Page 69. The Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Canal Company, $5.00 note #3492 issued in Frederick, MD on September 9, 1840. Page 70. DUTIES ACCOUNT LEDGER "Light Houses (To be Erected on Chesapeake Bay &amp; Potomac River in a/c with James M. Lingan / (?) Officer of the Ninth District for Duty received on Tonage of Vessels since the first Day of October (?)," January 1, 1787, George Town. Submitted by James McCubbin Lingan (1751-1812) documenting duties totaling £43.87 imposed on arriving vessels between October 7 and December 1, 1786. Page 73. ILLUSTRATIONS "Aqueduct near Georgetown," color illustration. Page 9. "Bridge Street Presbyterian Church, corner Bridge and Washington streets, Georgetown," undated newspaper clipping. Page 52. Engravings of Georgetown and Georgetown College, DC, undated clipping. Page 56. "General view of Georgetown College in 1880 from an old print in Century Magazine," undated newspaper clipping. Page 52. "Georgetown College, DC, published by C. Bohn, 1850," undated clipping. Page 54. "Map of Washington as the city appeared in 1877…" Clipping from the Washington Post, December 6, 1927. Page 56. "Old Beall House, Georgetown Heights," black and white photograph of 1633 31st Street, NW, "moved about 1800 from Mackall Square." Page 11. "Old Georgetown Bridge [Aqueduct Bridge]. Looking north from the bridge toward Georgetown University oat the time of the Centenary celebration of the university, February 20, 1889. From a photograph by C. M. Bell," undated newspaper clipping. Page 54. "The Old C.A.C. track on Analostan Island. Scene of the League of American Wheelmen bicycle races, July, 1892," undated newspaper clipping. Page 52. "View of Washington from Signal Camp, Georgetown Heights, During the War," (Reservoir site – R &amp; Wisconsin Avenue), black and white illustration. Page 9. Washington &amp; Georgetown Railroad horse-drawn streetcar, Capitol via Pennsylvania Avenue and 14th Street, NW, undated newspaper clipping. Page 52. INVITATIONS Cooke [Henry D.], Governor and Mrs., February 18, [1873]. "At Home" from 9:00 pm to "Twelve ½ Past, Dancing" at 170 Washington Street (1517 30th Street, NW). Page 7. Georgetown Classical and Mathematical Academy, July 29, 1842. Exhibition held at the Methodist Protestant Church issued to Mr. Meem. Page 64. Georgetown College, July 24, 1845. Commencement held in College Hall signed by Samuel Mulledy, President. Page 60. Independent Grays, January 17, 1843. First annual military and civic ball held in the Assembly Room of Georgetown's Union Hotel. Page 62. Female Seminary, July 23, 1842. Sent to Mr. Craigin to "attend an examination of the pupils." Page 5. Female Seminary, 1842. To Philip T. Berry in the amount of $14.45 ½ for tuition and supplies for Mary Ellen Berry and $10.62 ½ for tuition and extras for L. Alice Berry. Page 6. Female Seminary, 1847. Two invoices sent to Mr. H[enry] C. Matthews in the amount of $5.00 for tuition and $6.62 for tuition and extras for Mary Catherine Matthews. Page 8. McCleary (?), Henry (?), 1808. To John Ott in the amount of $8.64 for "…expenses attending the transportation of (?) Forte from the (?) in (?) to George Town." Page 66. LETTERS Headquarters Eastern Department, Governors Island, New York City to Librarian, Peabody Room, March 20, 1918. "Confidential" request to remove "all books on explosives" and to report the names/address of individuals requesting such materials. Page 21. LICENSES Corporation of Georgetown. Issued June 30, 1817 to Lewis G. Davidson for the period of one year to "…keep one male white dog within the jurisdiction of the Corporation of Georgetown…" Signed by John Mountz, Clerk and John Peter, Mayor. Page 40 NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS "Annexation," Georgetown Courier, December 16, 1865. Page 25. "Annexation or Retrocession," Georgetown Courier, December 9, 1865. Page 25. "City Councils," Georgetown Courier, 1865. Page 30. Corcoran, William Wilson. Poem "To W.W. Corcoran," Georgetown Courier, April 9, 1870. Page 34. "Compliment to a Certain Grocer," unknown newspaper and date. A twenty line poem written by "Water Street" that disparage a man named Scott. Accompanied by an illustration of a cat wearing glasses. Page 66. Davidson, Samuel. "Evermay Proclaims," Independent American, June 2, 1810. Classified advertisement warning against trespassing on property. Page 3. "Election of Corporation Officers," Georgetown Courier, January 6, 1866. Page 32. "Farmers' and Mechanics' Bank," Georgetown Courier, April 1870. (Classified advertisement.) Page. 25. "The Georgetown Courier," December 30, 1865. (Subscription information notice.) Page. 25. Hein, C. S. Classieified ad for "Artist and Professor of Drawing," Georgetown Courier, 1870. Page 30. "Ordinances of the Corporation of Georgetown," Georgetown Courier, January 6, 1866. Listing of a resolution and ordinance "Resolved by the Board of Aldermen and the Board of Common Council of the Corporation of Georgetown." Page 32. Peabody, George. San Antonio Evening News, February 18, 1936. Brief biography of George Peabody. Inside front cover. "The Peabody Room," Gordon News, May 1936. Page 19. "A Reminder of Old Days in Georgetown," Georgetown News, April 3, 1936. View of the Georgetown waterfront. Page 11. "Reminiscences of Georgetown," Georgetown Courier, December 23, 1865. .) Pages 27-29. "A Resolution...," Georgetown Courier, 1865. Listing of seven resolutions "Resolved by the Board of Aldermen and the Board of Common Council of the Corporation of Georgetown." Page 30. "Union Hotel," Georgetown Courier, April 1870. (Classified advertisement.) Page. 25. Vinson, Charles. "New Store," Independent American, June 2, 1810. Listing of goods available for sale at new business located on Bridge (M) Street. Page 36. "Vision of Industrialist Finds Fruition in Georgetown Library…," Evening Star, January 12, 1936. Pages 17-19. Washington, George. "Washington Entombed," Ulster County New York Gazette, January 4, 1800. Article dateline "George Town, Dec. 20" about the recent death of George Washington. Page 1. NOTICES Battalion Parade, undated. Issued to Alexander Guy from Captain Cruickshank to be "completely equipped for inspection." Page 4. PERIODICAL CLIPPINGS "Love Song to a Washington Real Estate Man," by Agnes Burke Hale, The New Yorker, January 8, 1944. Page 72. PHOTOGRAPHS Gen. John Mason's House, Anolostan Island. Gelatin silver photograph of abandoned house. Page 75. Suter's Tavern. Gelatin silver photograph of illustration of the tavern. Page 75. POLITICAL CAMPAIGN MEMORABILIA Harrison, William Henry and John Tyler 1840 silk campaign ribbon issued by the Georgetown, DC delegation proclaiming "The Liberty of Speech, if not the Right of Suffrage." Page 58. PROGRAMS St. John's Church. Benefit program held at the Curtis School, May 1, 1878. Page 16. PROMISSORY NOTES Gaither, Col. Henry. Issued May 28, 1811 to Gaither by Lewis G. Davidson in the amount of $555.33. Page 44. Key, Francis S. Issued January 24, 1833 to Key by James S. Morsell in the amount of $2,300. Page 38. RECEIPTS Beall, Col. George, June 17, 1796. To James S. Morsell in the amount of £116 (pounds) for one year of boarding, firewood, and "cash paid Mr. Beale." Page 68. Berry, Philip T., April 20, 1819. To Lewis G. Davidson (and possibly Richard Osbourn) in the amount of $11.25 for kersey and lambs wool. Page 42. Bootes, A.A. &amp; E., July 5, 1836. To Mrs. Guy in the amount of $4.00 for one quarter tuition for her daughter. Page 49. Burnett, Charles Alexander, November 21, 1817. To Lewis G. Davidson for the $210 purchase of a gold patent lever watch and chain. Page 46. Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Canal Company, December 3, 1828. To John S. Haw in the amount of $25 for the 4th installment on ten shares of stock. Signature of cashier at Farmers &amp; Mechanics Ban is illegible. Page 3. Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Canal Company, December 13, 1830. To George Davis in the amount of $12.50 for the (?) installment on one share of stock. Signature of cashier at Farmers &amp; Mechanics Ban is illegible. Page 74. Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Canal Company, November 7, 1835. To John S. Haw and Philip T. Berry in the amount of $100 for the (?) installment on ten shares of stock. Signature of cashier at Farmers &amp; Mechanics Ban is illegible. Page 70. Clarke, Dr. George, 1813. To Lewis G. Davidson for $15.00 worth of medical services provided to Davidson and his "servant man." Page 48. Corporation of Georgetown, July 6, 1839. To William Morgan in the amount of $2.25 for 1839 taxes on property valued at $300 at ¾ (?) cent. Penciled notation indicates that this address was 3132 O Street, NW. Page 74. English, Lydia S., July 13, 1831. To Mrs. Guy in the amount of $5.12 1/5 for tuition and supplies at Miss English's Seminary. Page 4. Federal Republican, May 5, 1814. To Lewis G. Davidson for $5.00 in payment for subscription from August 8, 1812 to August 8, 1813. Signed by Robert Allen. Page 40. Illegible signature, March 25, 1818. To Lewis G. Davidson for the $575 purchase of a "yellow bay named Cornelious which I warrant the property of said Davidson for life." Witnessed by Peter Brady. Page 42. Illegible signature, March 25, 1838. To Trustees of the Lancaster School for the $1.00 purchase of five 10" x 12" glazing. Page 49. Jewell, William, 1817. To Lewis G. Davidson for $68.12 worth of clothing, alterations and repairs. Page 50. Lutz, John, 1817. To Lewis G. Davidson for the $13.00 purchase of a saddle and other illegible items. Page 46. Peabody, John, March 30, 1819. To Lewis G. Davidson for the $14.00 purchase of a bureau. Page 46. Peerce (?), C. (?), February 9, 1818. To Lewis G. Davidson for the $10.00 purchase of clothing. Page 48. Presbyterian Congregation, 1818. To Lewis G. Davidson for $10.00 in payment for a half year subscription to the Trustees of the Presbyterian Congregation ending April 1819. Page 44. Reynolds, William, March 2, 1819. To Lewis G. Davidson for receipt of $6.66 in payment of debt. Reynolds signature in form of "his mark" (an "X"). Witnessed by John Easter. Page 40. Tenney, Caroline, August 2, 1831. To Mrs. N. Guy in the amount of $3.00 for tuition. Page 4. Washington, Alexandria, and Georgetown Steam Packet Company, June 4, 1842. To Rind (?), Curator National Institute, in the amount of $5.53 for freight charges of a large box from Baltimore containing specimens. Page 70. Wheatley, F., December 31, 1840. To Mrs. Guy in the amount of $1.62 for services. Receipt features imprinted letterhead, "F. WHEATLEY, Silk, Woolen, and Cotton Dying – Bleaching and Cloth Dresser. West side of Jefferson Street, Georgetown." Page 74. TELEGRAMS Mechlin, J. R. Poinset in New York, NY to his son, William Mechlin, in Washington, DC. Transmitted April 20, 1852 by the Magnetic Telegraph Company. Includes original envelope. Page 23. TICKETS Georgetown Collegiate Institute. "Soiree" held at 46 First Street on February 10, 1876. Page 49. St. John's Church. "Noctes Ambrosianae" held at the Cooke Mansion, corner of 30th and Q Street [3005 Q Street, NW] on November 17-19, 1886. Page 56.</p>
    </index>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
